A Guide to the Washington Times: "The Civil War", 1996-2005
Thomas Balch Library
- (Box 3)
  - "Arlington Ridge Sees War's Beginning, End," "North, South Find Support Among Jews," n.d.
  - "Booth's Oil-Field Venture Goes Bust," "Two City Landmarks Built Amid Turmoil," "House of Good Repute: Brothel Pampered Elite," n.d.
  - "Hunt for Mosby Bloodies California Hundred," "'Conductors' On This Railroad Earn Hero Status," n.d.
  - "Winning the Hearts and Minds Up North," "Illustrious Past Comes Alive Again," n.d.
  - "Gripping Account of Fredericksburg's 'Winter War,'" "Context Lost in Bio of Dashing 'Rooney,'" n.d.
  - "Yule Joy Spreads to Rebel," "Santa Springs from the Pens of Moore, Nest," "Conflict of Lasting Interest to Novelists," n.d.
  - "Stanton Sent Ex-Journalist to 'Spy' on Grant," "Battle at Martinsburg Hinges on Delay," n.d.
  - "Bronze Reveals Courage and Character of Grant," "Bolder Meede Pursues, Captures Lee," "Lincoln's Family Among Those Split for Battle," n.d.
  - "Star Witness a Rebel With a Union Cause," "Tipsters, Cranks Hot on Trail of Booth," n.d.
  - "Power Couple of Confederacy Survives Defeat," "Author Takes Us Along on Lee's Retreat," n.d.
  - "Efforts Ensure Dead Not Forgotten," "A Unique Honor for 2 Unique Heroes," "'Annie Laurie' and Lonely Soldiers," n.d.
  - "Museum Seeks to Portray Conflict in Its Entirety," "New Insights on the Complex Paths That Led to Horrific Overland Campaign," n.d.
  - "Bearss Outranks Many as Battlefield Historian," "Lincoln's Legacy Goes Beyond U.S. Borders," n.d.
  - "Lawmaker Gives Constituent Grant His Start," "Rebels Capture Blacks While Invading North," n.d.
  - "Yellow Fever Tests One Man's Courage," "New Look at Some Familiar Battles," n.d.
  - "Timing is Everything, as Antietam Proves," n.d.
  - "Canadian Haven and Home for Fugitive Slaves," "America's Northern Neighbor and the War," n.d.
  - "Richmond's Belle Isle a Rival to Andersonville," n.d.
  - "South's Horse Shortage Hobbles Cavalry Tactics," "Jams Gets Start in Guerilla Fighting," n.d.
  - "Mountain's Gold Set Another Battleground," "Positive Buzz Over 'Gods and Generals,'" n.d.
  - "Northern Neck Target of Frequent U.S. Attacks," "Men of Snow's Battery Drawn from a Divided Cecil County," n.d.
  - "Lee's Biographer is a Story Himself," "Seward Home Scene of Acts of Violence," "Wiegel's 'Gallant' Service Includes Raising Flag," n.d.
  - "D.C. Within South's Grasp After Early Rout," "U.S. Navy pays Homage to Its 'Father,'" n.d.
  - "Marriage Starts Bride Down Aisle to Misery," "Leading Ladies: Different Sides, Like Traits," n.d.
  - "Four Swing From Gallows for Lincoln's Murder," n.d.
  - "Exhaustive Look at Gettysburg Worth Length," "Rebels Find a Willing Spy in 17-Year-Old," n.d.
  - "Defeated Rebels Find New Causes," "Back to 1860s on USS Constellation," "The Assassination and 'That Dreadful' Theater," n.d.
  - "Treasury Rooms Prove Historical Treasures," "Blacks, Jews Fight on Side of the South," n.d.
  - "The Great Cavalry Clash at Brandy Station," "Wherever Sickness Goes, Trouble Follows," n.d.
  - "Military Records Include Rebels," "Legacy of a Lincoln Secretary," "A Look at Conflict Through Eyes of British Officer," n.d.
  - "General's Fiery Ties to Land of My Family," "Rebel Story Just a Good Yarn," n.d.
  - "Grant Wins Last Battle By Finding Memoirs," "Congress Beats Clock to Aid Grant," "Two Infantrymen Follow 2 Roads to Gettysburg," n.d.
  - "Writers' Military Experience Colors Later Works," n.d.
  - "Act of Battlefield Chivalry Never Forgotten," "Doctor Becomes Leader of Horse Artillery," n.d.
  - "A Piece of Metal Tells Story of Private," "Black Reporter's Blow for Equality," n.d.
  - "Painter's Artistic Six Months with Lincoln," "Memorial to Tragedy of June 17, 1864," n.d.
  - "People Still Wonder About Old South Ball," "Raiders Said to Have Partied in Maryland," n.d.
  - "Rebel's Success as Romeo Costly to Unit," "Union Pays Dearly for Gains at Chantilly," n.d.
  - "Two Forces Fight 'Brother's War' in Loudoun," "Somber Visit to Grave No. 898," n.d.
  - "Blazer's Scouts Picked Away at Confederacy," "Clear View of Pickett's Charge," n.d.
  - "Land Still Yields Bullets from Crampton's Gap Battle," n.d.
- (Box 4)
  - "Two Brothers Lead Rebel Guerilla Raids," n.d.
  - "Questioning Rebels Pays Off at Gettysburg," "Major Private Museum to U.S.," n.d.
  - "Border States Legislate Slavery End," "Mosby Raids Herndon Outpost," n.d.
  - "U.S. Agents Give Special Europe Service," "Old Papers Soon to be Online," n.d.
  - "Soldier's Ashes, On Shelf 85 Years, Finally Go Home," n.d.
  - "Slave Preacher was 'Gospel Warrior,'" n.d.
  - "Newsman Villard Eyewitness to History," n.d.
  - "Ex-Union Officer Leads Re-Enactment," "Rebellious Dr. Mary Walker," n.d.
  - "A Sibling Hunts for Brother's Body," n.d.
  - "17-Year Effort Saves Harpers Ferry Park," "Respect for Bristoe's Fallen," "Fight to Preserve Battlefields Continues," n.d.
  - "Officers Serve in Three Navies Within U.S.," "Lincoln Gains Status of Myth in Death," n.d.
  - "Fight for Battlefield Preservation Goes On," n.d.
  - "Greenback Raid Builds Mosby's Legend," "Fresh Look at Assassination Story," n.d.
  - "Battlefield Corpses Treated with Respect," "Luck Runs Out for Raider Sumter," n.d.
  - "Sheridan's Ride Helps Turn 1864 Vote," "Emotional Report in Paper Aids Daring General's Image," n.d.
  - "Connecticut Private Marched into Many Battles, Promotions," "Into the Fray Over Lee's 'Audacity,'" n.d.
  - "Cleveland Loses the Battle of Rebel Flags," "Combat, Politics and Valiant Deeds," n.d.
  - "Early's Summer March Chills Washington," "Rockville Events Recall 1864 Action," n.d.
  - "Lincoln Uses Religion to Advance War Aims," "British Prizewinner Makes Own History," "Preserving the Earthworks," n.d.
  - "Journey into Souls of Two Excellent Men," "Chaplain's Plains Legacy on the Line," n.d.
  - "Brothers Team Up to Calm Hotheads," "Stone for Lincoln's Nearly Lost: Inscribed Roman Tribute Sent Before 1865 Killing of President," "Composer's Tribute Poorly Received," n.d.
  - "Six Hundred Suffer North's POW Cruelty: Rebels Held in Firing Zone," "Cyclorama Restoration Part of Larger Effort," n.d.
  - "Davis' Early Picks Got Command On Both Sides," "Imboden's Raids Bedevil Federals," n.d.
  - "Civilians Fall Victim at Bloody Antietam," "Officers Lead and Die by Example," n.d.
  - "Grant fooled, But Lee Misses 'Masterstroke,'" "Toy Store Brightens Lincoln's Days," n.d.
  - "Scott a Pompous But Able Professional," "Reader Can Weigh Conspirators' Guilt: The Assassination of President Lincoln and the Trial of the Conspirators," n.d.
  - "As Fight Ends, Military Surplus Up for Sale," "Cousins' Tales Reveal Family Divided," n.d.
  - "Michigan Warriors Brave Three-Side Battle Bayonets Retain Colors in Virginia," "New Orleans a Port of Vital Significance," n.d.
  - "Lee Builds Campaigns on Information," "Vigilant Envoy Finally Stops Ship After Attacks End," n.d.
  - "Touring the Sites of Stuart's Exploits," "Davis' Camels a 'Hi Jolly' Glory: Syrian Driver Helped Prove Their Worth Over Horses, Mules," n.d.
  - "Defiant Texans Models Badge of Courage," "Mighty Clash Rattles the Sabers of Political, Professional Generals," "Marker Heralds Nuns' Contributions," n.d.